# Sherwin Laconsay

Network Analyst | NOC Engineer

#### CONTACT



902-224-5851



sherwinlaconsay@gmail.com



Lower Sackville, NS, Canada



www.linkedin.com/in/s-laconsay/

## **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATES**

NOVA SCOTIA COMMUNITY COLLEGE Diploma in IT Systems Management & Security (On-going)

ROGATIONIST COLLEGE, PHILIPPINES BS in Electronics Engineering 2014

Cisco CCNA | ID No. CSC012726641 2015 - 2018

### **SKILLS**

# ✓ NETWORK OPERATION

- Change Requests Management
- Fault Ticket Handling
- Root Cause Analysis
- Domestic Fiber Optic Network
- Access & Core Network
- NMS & OSS

# ✓ DATA HANDLING & AUTOMATION

- Python
- MS Power Automate
- MySQL
- Excel
- PowerBi
- Tableau

### ✓ SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATION

- Windows (Client and Server)
- Linux (Server)
- VirtualBox

# ✓ SECURITY

- Firewall Configurations
- Basic Penetration Testing

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a proficient Network Analyst with a strong passion for ICT, automation, and network operations. My experience includes multitasking, network change management, troubleshooting, report and process automation, data collection, and visualization. I consistently achieve and exceed performance targets while fostering a positive and collaborative work environment.

### **EXPERIENCE**

PLDT INC. – Metro Manila, Philippines

Senior Network Performance Analyst (NOC), Oct 2015 – Apr 2023

- Managed network changes for PLDT's Domestic and International network, ensuring compliance and minimizing customer issues.
- Processed over 6,000 change request tickets annually, covering various aspects like capacity management and network operability.
- Investigated 70,000 network outage tickets yearly using advanced tools to improve KPI projections.
- Used OSS and NMS tools for efficient network monitoring and incident handling.
- Developed automated KPI reports and dashboards using Python,
   Tableau, and Microsoft tools.
- Addressed stakeholder inquiries promptly to ensure customer satisfaction.
- Provided critical support in a 24/7 Network Operations Center for uninterrupted network functioning.

PLDT INC. – Metro Manila, Philippines **Assistant Project Engineer**, Jan 2014 – June 2015

- Collaborated with PLDT project engineers on product type approval, proof of concept (POC), and acceptance testing.
- Evaluated procured hardware, such as Fiber Optic Cables, OLT modems, DSL, and VDSL modems, and network test equipment with comprehensive test cases and analysis of specifications.
- Generated detailed reports with valuable insights from testing data for decision-making.